Radek Kříček, PhD

TECH STACK

Python · SQL · R

Tableau · Grafana · Git · DBeaver ·

Google Cloud Console · VS Code ·

RStudio · Jupyter Notebook ·

MS Excel · Google Sheets

Pandas · NumPy · SciPy · SQLAlchemy ·

Matplotlib · Seaborn · Dash

TRAINING / COURSES

Data Analytics Course

Praha Coding School (SQL, Python, Tableau, Grafana)

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Google, Coursera (SQL, R, Tableau, Spreadsheets)

LANGUAGES

Czech (Slovak) Native

English C2 level

German Advanced

Spanish Beginner

HOBBIES

Volunteering in environmentalism and human rights

Field monitoring of wolves, member of the council of Friends of the Earth CZ, lobbying for gay marriage

Astronomy, science outreach

Watching the sky and sharing the wonder (supported Czech Astronomy Olympiad and more)

Hiking

Be it Lausitzer Gebirge or Grand Teton

Data Analyst

- \ +49 1525 8610831 @ radek.kricek@gmail.com
- @www.linkedin.com/in/radek-kricek/ @www.github.com/radek-kricek

SUMMARY

Through my work, I strive to protect the future of nature and people. I see data analytics as the next step on my journey to change the world for better using fact-based decisions, and to grow professionally.

I bring passion for sustainability, strong technical background, experience with data-based decision making and effective communication to the table.

EXPERIENCE

Trainee Data Analytics

06/2023 - 08/2023

Spiced Academy, Berlin, DE

Berlin, Germany

- Intense full-time coding bootcamp in Data Analytics.
- · Perfected coding in Python and PostgreSQL.
- Mastered data analysis, Python libraries, database clients and data visualization (Tableau).
- Business intelligence, KPIs.

Manager of Data Collection

10/2018 - 05/2023

Friends of the Earth CZ

Olomouc, Czechia

- Managed field data collection on biodiversity, performed data quality assurance (controlled over 600 observation results of protected species).
- Supported an international project with over 30 organizations from 7 European countries, focused on data-driven decision making in landscape connectivity.
- Responsible for project activities worth €200,000.
- Led a project team of 5-10 co-workers.
- Established activities in the region, developed PR, educated and coordinated volunteers.
- · Dealt with variety of stakeholders.

Science Communicator

09/2018 - 08/2021

Czech Academy of Sciences

Prague, Czechia

- Reached out to thousands of citizens representing the public, students and teachers.
- · Organized over 30 outreach events.
- Created press releases, articles and social media content.

Teacher of Mathematics and Physics

08/2015 - 06/2018

Johannes Kepler Grammar School

Prague, Czechia

• Gave 900 lessons of math and physics at a prestigious grammar school.

EDUCATION

PhD: Didactics of Physics

2014 - 2019

Charles University, Prague, Czechia

- Analyzed qualitative and quantitative data from hundreds of respondents (questionnaires, interviews, case studies, A/B testing, k-means and more).
- Gained strong foundation in mathematics, statistics and effective communication.